# RITA PECUCH

Fenton, MI

#### **SUMMARY**

Motivated and organized Full Stack Web Developer with a background in biology and healthcare. Passionate about utilizing problem solving to develop user-friendly applications and always striving to learn new skills. Known by instructors, employers, and colleagues for leadership, teamwork, and high attention to detail. HIPAA-certified and possesses extensive healthcare industry knowledge including electronic health records, medical facility procedures, medical terminology, and human subject research.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Python, C#, HTML, CSS

Back End Technologies: MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Express, GraphQL, Apollo, Restful

APIs, Sequelize, Mongoose

Front End Technologies: React, Node.js, Document Object Model, Bootstrap, Material UI,

jQuery

### **PROJECTS**

### My Kids RX | my-kids-rx.herokuapp.com/ | github.com/rpecuch/kids-rx-info

- Patient portal that allows parents of pediatric patients to keep track of health records online, as well as provide entertainment for pediatric patients.
- Team leader, built back end and added sample data, developed GraphQL queries and mutations, wrote logic for three games, implemented login
- Tools / languages: MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, GraphQL, Material UI, JavaScript, CSS

### Kids RX | kids-rx-emr.herokuapp.com | github.com/rpecuch/kids-rx-info

- Electronic health record system specifically designed for use in pediatrics.
- Team leader, built back end and added sample data, wrote GET, POST, PUT, and DELETE API requests, implemented login
- Tools / languages: MySQL, Sequelize, Express, Node.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, CSS

## Virtual Party Mom | rpecuch.github.io.virtual-party | github.com/rpecuch/virtual-party

- Application that allows the user to check the weather and retrieve suggestions for group activities based on the current weather conditions.
- Team leader, wrote GET requests to five APIs and handled data display, wrote logic for Cards Against Humanity game
- Tools / languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

#### EXPERIENCE

**Bioinformatics Lab Assistant** 

June 2022 - Present

**Oakland University** 

Rochester, MI

- Analyzes large biological datasets using Python programming, Roary, and BioPerl modules
- Works with DNA sequences up to 5000000 base pairs in length
- Runs statistical analyses using Python, Matplotlib, and NumPy

# Lead Medical Assistant

June 2019 - May 2022

**Aljundi Medical PLLC** 

Waterford, MI

Analyzed and improved office protocols, including optimizing the use of electronic health record system. Recruited and trained new staff members. Demonstrated multi-tasking and ability to work under pressure to fulfill the needs of many patients at once. Key Accomplishments:

- After working as a staff Medical Assistant was promoted to leadership role
- Within 1 month of promotion, increased number of appointments by 5-10 per day and decreased money owed to physician by approximately \$2000

### **Nursing Assistant**

August 2018 - January 2019

**Wellbridge of Rochester Hills** 

Rochester Hills, MI

- Demonstrated ability to work under pressure in a fast-paced environment by providing high-quality care to 15-18 patients at a time
- EHR/EMR charting
- Provided assistance with activities of daily living and took vital signs

#### **EDUCATION**

Boot Camp Certificate: Rutgers University, Camden, NJ

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills.

#### Bachelor of Science in Biomedical Sciences: Oakland University, Rochester, MI

- Maintained a 4.0 cumulative science GPA, 3.97 overall GPA
- President and Co-Founder of the Society for Pre-Anesthesia Professionals that received New Student Organization of the Year
- Key Awards: Outstanding New Student Organization President, Undergraduate Research Grant, Barry S. Winkler Scholarship, Presidential Scholarship